# Haozhe XU

email: haozhe.xu3@gmail.com

website: <a href="http://www.huiimy.ninja">http://www.ninja</a>
GitHub: <a href="http://www.github.com/haozhexu">http://www.github.com/haozhexu</a>
LinkedIn: <a href="http://au.linkedin.com/in/haoever">http://au.linkedin.com/in/haoever</a>

Mobile: +61 412 735 999

### **Professional Statement**

I'm a highly skilled Mobile Developer with 6 years of commercial iOS development experience. I possess specialised knowledge of different aspects of iOS development and software development life cycle in general. With the experience being developer as well as tech lead I have come to obtain a unique set of skills including iOS development, agile methodology, team leading, team collaboration and so on.

### Education

March 2008 - June 2009

#### Postgraduate Diploma in Science (Computer Science)

Thesis: Staged Event-Driven Architecture on Mobile Devices (J2ME)

The University of Melbourne, Parkville

March 2005 - December 2007

#### **Bachelor of Computer Science**

The University of Melbourne, Parkville

## **Employment History**

July 2011 - Present

#### **Outware Mobile - Senior Software Developer**

Lead developer for AFL Live Official App

Lead developer for NRL Live Official App

Lead developer for Cricket Live Official App

Team leading junior developers on iOS development

Performing regular technical interviews, involved in software architecture design.

January 2010 - May 2011 (1.5 years)

#### Self-Employed iPhone Game Developer

Game apps (now removed from AppStore as developer account discontinued): Tris Revenge, Manga Jump, Dejeweled, Brave Birds, screenshots available upon request.

2008-2009 (2 years)

#### Hobbyist Java Developer (J2SE, J2ME)

Swing GUI Design

Products: MTextReader (Editor's Pick Award from Brothersoft), BlueBuddy

## **Professional Applications**

Sportsbet for iPad (iOS)

Developer. Using RESTful services.

https://itunes.apple.com/au/app/sportsbet-for-ipad/id586105288?mt=8

Cricket Live Official App (iOS)

Lead developer. Using RESTful services.

https://itunes.apple.com/au/app/cricket-australia-live-official/id720516760

NRL LIVE (iOS)

Lead developer. Using RESTful services.

https://itunes.apple.com/au/app/official-nrl-2012/id442363523?mt=8

**AFL Live Official App** (iOS)

Lead developer. Using RESTful services.

https://itunes.apple.com/au/app/afl-live-official-app/id415427158?mt=8

## Personal Projects

I've made several iOS games in my spare time, but my developer account was discontinued so they are currently not in AppStore, below is a new one I've made recently:

**ImSucker** (iOS) - An app that generates poems following ancient China poetry pattern and style.

https://itunes.apple.com/app/wo-shi-sao-ke/id963419023?mt=8

Retro Blocks (iOS) - Retro style block matching game.

https://itunes.apple.com/app/id917655100?mt=8

fortune I cowsay (iOS) - Mimic the classic fortune and cowboy program on Unix.

https://itunes.apple.com/app/fortune-cowsay/id1016269563

East Solitaire (iOS) - Ancient Chinese pebble game.

https://itunes.apple.com/app/east-solitaire/id1244283234

### Certificates

Sun Certified Java Programmer (SCJP) - 2003

Sun Certified Java Developer (SCJD) - 2004

Sun Certified Web Component Developer (SCWCD) - 2004